[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Well let's look at an algorithm for doing clustering that uses this
那么 让我们来看一个聚类算法
metric of just looking at the distance to the cluster center.
它用到的度量标准是只看与集群中心的距离
Okay, so here, we see the data that we're gonna wanna cluster.
好的 现在我们这里看到的是我们想要分类的数据
And this algorithm, which is called the k-means algorithm,
这个算法 我们称为k均值
starts by assuming that you are gonna end up with k clusters.
我们从最终将得到k个集群的假设出发
So you specify the number of clusters ahead of time.
也就是说你需要提前给定最终集群的数量
So the reason the algorithm is called k-means is we have k clusters, and
所以这个算法之所以叫k均值是因为我们有k个集群 并且
we're looking at the means of the clusters, just the cluster centers,
我们会看每个集群的平均值 只考虑集群中心
when we're assigning points to the different clusters.
以此来将数据点分到不同的集群中
Okay, so let's talk about how we initialize the algorithm.
好的 让我们来谈谈如何初始化这个算法吧
So the first thing we do is we just one example.
我们首先来举个例子
There are many ways to initialize where we put the cluster centers.
我们有很多种方法来初始化集群中心的位置
We will talk about these things more in-depth later.
我们一会儿将会更深入地讲这些问题
But for now,
但现在但现在
let's just assume that we randomly assigned three different cluster centers.
让我们暂时假设我们会随机选出3个不同的集群中心
If we're going to assume some, three means algorithm here.
如果我们来跑一个3均值算法
And then the first step is we're going to assign every observation
那么第一步就是把所有的数据点分给
to the closest cluster center.
离它最近的集群中心
So this observation here gets assigned to the red cluster.
因此这里的这个数据点会被分到红色集群中去
These observations are all closest to the green cluster, or this green center here.
这些数据点全都离绿色集群或者说这个绿色中心点最近
And these are all closest to the blue center.
然后这些都离蓝色中心点最近
And a way to do this is something that's just called a Voronoi tessellation.
而做这些判定的一个方法叫做沃罗诺伊镶嵌算法
So we look at the cluster centers and well, we can do our define,
接下来我们看集群中心 我们可以进行定义了
let me switch again to this magenta color.
这里我再换成洋红色的笔
So here the cluster centers.
这里是集群中心
And we can just define these regions here.
我们就可以定义这里这些区域
And these regions represent areas where any observation we might get,
而这些区域代表任何我们可能得到的数据点的范围
so any new observation, that's a very bad color on red.
对于任何的数据点 - 这个颜色在红色背景下效果真烂
What other colors do I have?
我有什么别的颜色呢？
How about white?
白色怎么样？
Cool, white.
很好 白色
So some new observation I get here, if it falls within this red region,
所以我得到的某个观测值 如果它在这个红色的区域里
I know it's closest to this red cluster center.
我就知道它是离这个红色集群中心最近的一个
So that's what these colored regions are representing.
所以这就是这些填色的区域所代表的意思
Okay so, that's the first step of the algorithm.
好的，那这就是算法的第一步
So, what I end up with are observations that are assigned to clusters.
然后这些区域代表任何我们可能观测到的点所在的范围
But I just randomly initialize those clusters centers, so I probably don't
不过由于这些初始的集群中心都是随机生成的 所以我不会觉得它们
believe that that really represents the structure underlying the data.
反映了数据的真实情况
So what I wanna do is I wanna iterate this process, where I then wanna update what my
所以接下来我们想要让这个流程循环下去
definition is of the cluster center based on the observations that I've assigned.
一遍又一遍地根据数据点的分配情况 更新集群中心的位置
So if you remember this red cluster here,
所以如果你还记得这个红色的中心的话
it just had one observation assigned to it.
它只有被分到一个观测值
So when I go to revise the cluster center for that cluster,
所以当我修正那个集群的集群中心时
it just moves to the previous observation.
这个中心就跑到了之前那个唯一的点上了
But for this green cluster, if I look at the previous cluster center here,
而对于这个绿色集群来说 这里是中心原来的位置
well I'm gonna move it to the center of mass of all
我们要把它移到这里
these observations that have been assigned to the green cluster.
所有被分到绿色集群的 这些点的中心位置
And the center of mass of all of them is here,
这里就是这些绿点的中心
so this becomes the new cluster center.
这就是新的集群中心的位置
And likewise, I do this for all of the blue observations.
同样的道理，我们也要更新蓝色中心的位置
This is the new cluster center for this blue observation.
这是蓝色观测点的新的集群中心
Okay, so now I have a new set of cluster centers.
那么现在我们有了一组新的集群中心
And what I can do is redraw this Voronoi tessellation, and
于是我就可以重新绘制一下 这幅沃罗诺伊图
reassign my observations to the nearest cluster center.
再把所有的观测点重新分配给 最近的集群中心
And then I iterate this process until convergence.
然后我将一直重复这个过程直到结果收敛
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community